# // Jason Paul Richmond

email: jason@richmond.is ~ text: 574.855.6954 ~ site: jason.richmond.is ~ date: 2024.01.22

Software Engineer with a Master's in Computer Science familiar with a diverse array of languages and platforms seeking opportunity to build upon eight years experience crafting applications and solving problems in startup and academic settings.

# **Professional Experience**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER, AUNALYTICS - SOUTH BEND, IN - 2021-2023

- Maintained the microservices and REST API of our data solutions platform written in Node using MongoDB, GraphQL, Hadoop, and Apache Pig
- Achieved subject matter expert in Formations, our in-house data portability framework
- Contributed to initiatives in improve the robustness and fault-tolerance of our data pipeline
- Committed features that sped up our data delivery by an order of magnitude allowing us to achieve our on-time delivery goal of 75 consecutive days
- Took the reins on implementing two-phase procedure for data manipulation so that only valid results would be written to the destination
- Investigated and coded dynamic solution to a logging failure impacting our deliverables
- Pushed for and piloted new team structure to better communicate and increase collaboration
- Engaged in designing our next generation platform written in Typescript using React

#### LEAD INSTRUCTOR, SOUTH BEND CODE SCHOOL - SOUTH BEND, IN - 2018-2020

- Crafted interactive learning path spanning eleven lessons of around 25k words in p5, giving students an introduction to procedural, object-oriented, and functional programming paradigms
- Laid a concrete foundation for primary and secondary school students to build out abstract programming concepts using Scratch, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, and Python
- Entrusted with running the Elkhart branch and being liaison to local schools keeping relevant stakeholders happy and extending Code School reach

#### LEARNING FACILITATOR, ACADEMIC CENTER FOR EXCELLENCE - SOUTH BEND, IN - 2016-2019

- Equipped dozens of graduates and undergraduates of all levels having trouble grokking the theory and practice of Computer Science with the knowledge and skills to succeed
- Debugged hundreds of student-written programs, usually on a tight deadline before submission without reference to a working answer
- Collaborated with professors to help compress the complex world of code into the tangible everyday for entry-level students

## Education

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE, INDIANA UNIVERSITY SOUTH BEND - 2021

 Studied a wide spectrum in the discipline, from artificial intelligence to algorithmic analysis, networking to neural networks, graphics to games, even writing the opcodes for a simulated CPU to run a puck-like robot with enough AI to navigate a maze

### Skills

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C, C++, C#, Go, SQL, Assembly
- Methodologies: CI/CD, TDD, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Gang of Four Design Patterns
- Tools: Node, React, Vue, Storybook, p5, Okta, GraphQL, MongoDB, Git, Docker, Jira
- Domains: UI/UX Design, Full-stack Development, Microservices, REST, Machine Learning, AI